SARAH HERZOG

github.com/Jiyambi/Portfolio | 07936 434640 | sarah.ann.herzog@gmail.com

Statement

I am a motivated, responsible, charismatic game programmer seeking a position where I can stretch my current abilities and learn new skills.

Though relatively new to the gaming industry, my wealth of life experiences through travel, a career in chemical engineering, and various teaching and freelance positions provide a unique background that is an asset to any creative endeavor. In addition to this colourful background, I am also highly focused on game programming and development, pursuing a degree at one of the most prestigious gaming universities in the world, University of Abertay.

I have shown myself to be hard working, imaginative, collaborative, and eager to learn throughout my university and work experiences. In short, I am an individual with a diverse skill set and strong technical background who is genuinely fascinated by games.

Skills

Languages

During my time at Portland State University, and later studying at Abertay, I became proficient in several coding languages. School projects resulted in extensive experience with C++ and Java, while my personal interests in Xbox and Windows indie game development lead me to experiment with C# and the XNA framework. My work at wow-pro.com provided a solid knowledge of Lua and an understanding of working with a game API.

Tools

In my previous career as a chemical engineer, I used many tools such as spreadsheets, presentations, and documents to convey technical information to non-technical audiences.

More recently at Portland State University, I learned programming and debugging on multiple platforms including Windows and Linux, using IDEs such as Visual Studio and Eclipse. I also compiled and debugged using command line interfaces including gcc/g++, gdb, and Valgrind. This experience served me well while working at Intel, where the integrated systems we were working on used only Linux command line.

While working with wow-pro.com, I learned and utilized version control through git, and managed a remote repository (using github.com) for a global team. I continued to use these tools throughout my time at university, as well as on personal projects.

I have also gained limited experience with several game libraries and engines including Allegro, DirectX, XNA, Flat Red Ball, and Havok.

Teamwork and Leadership

I participated in many group projects throughout my time at university, both as a leader and team member. At wow-pro.com, I led a team of international volunteers to develop a highly successful addon, many of which had no technical expertise. A small team of fellow interns at Intel and I created several tools to improve our QA process.

Communication

As a hobby, I maintain a blog covering various aspects of the gaming industry from a gamer and game developer prospective. This experience in educating and entertaining served me well as a science teacher, where I kept up to 20 primary school children engaged and interested for hours at a time. I also wrote, recorded, and voiced an informational video advertising the wow-pro.com addon.

On a more technical side, I co-authored an official report for a National Science Foundation education grant while working as an engineering education researcher at Oregon State University. In both my previous career and as a game programming student, I have been called upon multiple times to present results and projects for non-technical audiences, both in writing and as presentations.

SARAH HERZOG

github.com/Jiyambi/Portfolio | 07936 434640 | sarah.ann.herzog@gmail.com

Experience

7/2011 – 8/2012 | Quality Assurance Intern | Intel, Hillsboro OR

At Intel I was part of the quality assurance team responsible for testing a Flash plugin for Intel smart TV devices. During my time there I became proficient in set up, operation, and reporting for the testing procedure. I trained several new employees and helped develop multiple tools to streamline the process and improve team efficiency. Our efforts resulted in official certification for our platform from Adobe.

4/2010 – 12/2010 | Lead Addon Developer | www.wow-pro.com

Wow-pro.com, a popular fan website for World of Warcraft, tasked me with the development of an addon which would bring their strategy guides directly into the game. I lead an extensive, globe-spanning team of volunteers in the endeavor, resulting in a massively popular addon with over 200,000 downloads to date. Our product was recommended by several high profile websites within the WoW community, including WoW Insider (wow.joystiq.com). I also created a simplified language and lua-based interpreter, as well as a companion guide recording addon, to allow non-experts to create content.

Other Work

1/2010 – 9/2010 | Science Instructor | Mad Science, Seattle WA
6/2008 – 12/2008 | Engineering R&D Intern | ATI Wah Chang, Albany OR
9/2007 – 6/2008 | Engineering Education Research | OSU Chemical Engineering
4/2007 – 9/2007 | Facilities Engineering Intern | ON Semiconductor, Gresham OR
7/2006 – 11/2007 | Computer Technician | OSU Technology Support Services

Though not directly related to the gaming industry, my previous career gave me many valuable life experiences. At many of the companies I worked for I had a vital effect which changed them for the better, such as adding a new stage to the production process at Wah Chang, and implementing a piping change saving ON Semiconductor \$10,000 yearly. I gained familiarity with high responsibility situations, such as handling hazardous chemicals and operating powerful machinery. Finally, I gained experience presenting results, troubleshooting, and customer service – valuable skills in any industry.

Education

University of Abertay 2014 - MSc Computer Games Technology - In Progress

Portland State University 2012 – Advanced Degree Preparation (Computer Science)
Additional Coursework in Visual Design and Music

Oregon State University 2009 - BSc Chemical Engineering

Additional Coursework in Business Law, Marketing, and Entrepreneurship

Interests

Gaming: I play games daily, my current favorite being the indie hit Faster Than Light. I love the indie games scene, and my favorite game of all time is Bastion. I also play tabletop RPGs, card games, and board games.

Music: Relaxing for me means singing and playing folk music on my ukulele. In the USA I was a member of my university choir, and am known to break out into song without warning.

Writing: I keep a blog in my spare time, at jiyambi.blogpost.com, where I discuss gaming industry subjects from both a gamer and developer perspective. I use this as a vehicle to grow and improve myself professionally.

Sport: I enjoy martial arts, and obtained green belt in Chun Kuk Do karate in the USA. As a green belt, I assisted in teaching classes and competed in several tournaments.

Travel: Born and raised on the west coast of the USA, I've traveled all across my home country, Japan, Mexico, and to the UK where I am now studying. Experiencing different places and cultures keeps my perspective and ideas fresh